{"Topic": "Bihar", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "In which year was Jharkhand separated from Bihar?", "op1": "1998", "op2": "2000", "op3": "2002", "op4": "2004", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the State bird of Bihar?", "op1": "House Sparrow", "op2": "Hill Mynah", "op3": "Indian Roller", "op4": "Great Hornbill", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the following places in Bihar is the famous cattle fair held on Kartika Poornima?", "op1": "Gaya", "op2": "Rajgir", "op3": "Bhagalpur", "op4": "Sonepur", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The tomb of which historical ruler is located in Sasaram?", "op1": "Allaudin Khilji", "op2": "Aurangzeb", "op3": "Sher Shah Suri", "op4": "Qutubuddin Aibak", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following languages of Bihar uses the Tirhuta script?", "op1": "Bhojpuri", "op2": "Maithili", "op3": "Santali", "op4": "Angika", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following has founded the Sulabh International Museum of Toilets in New Delhi?", "op1": "Bindeshwar Pathak", "op2": "Anand Kumar", "op3": "Subhav Sinha", "op4": "Shaibal Gupta", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Chhath puja which is celebrated in Bihar is dedicated to which God?", "op1": "Indra", "op2": "Shiva", "op3": "Sun", "op4": "Krishna", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which district is the Vikramshila Gangetic Dolphin Sanctuary located?", "op1": "Bhagalpur", "op2": "Patna", "op3": "Buxar", "op4": "Nalanda", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who of the following persons from Bihar was known as the Mountain Man?", "op1": "Dasrath Manjhi", "op2": "Vashishtha Narayan Singh", "op3": "Brajkishore Prasad", "op4": "Anand Kumar", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following Sikh gurus was born in Patna?", "op1": "Guru Angad", "op2": "Guru Arjun Dev", "op3": "Guru Teg Bahadur", "op4": "Guru Gobind Singh", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following persons was nicknamed Lok Nayak?", "op1": "Jagjivan Ram", "op2": "Rajendra Prasad", "op3": "Jayaprakash Narayan", "op4": "Shri Krishna Sinha", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "At which of the following places does the river Kosi meet the Ganga?", "op1": "Kursela", "op2": "Vaishali", "op3": "Hazipur", "op4": "Jamalpur", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "On which day is the Bihar Diwas celebrated?", "op1": "20 January", "op2": "22 March", "op3": "23 June", "op4": "25 August", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who of the following was the founder of Nalanda University?", "op1": "Chandragupta I", "op2": "Samudragupta", "op3": "Chandragupta II", "op4": "Kumaragupta", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was known as Bihar Vibhuti?", "op1": "Jayaprakash Narayan", "op2": "Sahajanand Saraswati", "op3": "Anugrah Narayan Sinha", "op4": "Sri Krishna Singh", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The airport in Patna is named after which famous personality?", "op1": "Dr. Rajendra Prasad", "op2": "Jay Prakash Narayan", "op3": "Babu Jagjivan Ram", "op4": "Sri Krishna Singh", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "What was the original name of Hindi and Maithili poet Nagarjun?", "op1": "Vaidyanath Mishra", "op2": "Hari Mohan Jha", "op3": "Gajendra Thakur", "op4": "Ravindra Prabhat", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "What is the rank of Bihar in terms of population of Indian States?", "op1": "First", "op2": "Second", "op3": "Third", "op4": "Fourth", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which is the most populous tribe in Bihar?", "op1": "Gond", "op2": "Oraon", "op3": "Kharwar", "op4": "Santal", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which city is the Khuda Baksh Oriental library located?", "op1": "Patna", "op2": "Gaya", "op3": "Nalanda", "op4": "Bhagalpur", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Barauni Refinery in Bihar was built in collaboration with -", "op1": "France", "op2": "Germany", "op3": "Soviet Union", "op4": "South Korea", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who of the following is known as Maithil Kavi Kokil or the Poet Cuckoo of Maithili?", "op1": "Anamika", "op2": "Nagarjun", "op3": "Vidyapati", "op4": "SH Bihari", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Bihar ranks the lowest in terms of literacy as per 2011 census. What is the percentage of literates in the States as per the census?", "op1": "68.3%", "op2": "63.8%", "op3": "58.6%", "op4": "69.5%", "Answer": 2}]}